

# **Alisson Blaas**

# **Profile**

I've been a frontend engineer since 2018, I've worked with different frameworks in different project sizes. I also have experience in mobile development, leading teams, scalable projects, mvps, setting up projects from scratch

My main skills are: Reactjs, nextjs, react native, ionic, javascript, typescrit, git, github actions, material ui, styled components, redux, context API, zustand, GraphQL

# **Employment History**

#### Team Lead, UNPRESS, Austin

NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Developed many video features, thumbnails, asynchronous forms

As a team lead, I create cards in Jira, I align with the team what should be done, I mediate these situations between front and backend, in addition, I help on all fronts, backend, frontend, mobile, even though my specialty is frontend.

#### Frontend Engineer, GoFasti · Contract, Austin

NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

as a contract engineer, I was assigned to one of the companies that has a contract with gofasti called UNPRESS.

UNPRESS is located in austin, texas.

In this company I work with nextjs, Hooks, Typescript, Tailwind, React Query

# Senior Frontend Engineer, Caf, Pelotas

SEPTEMBER 2022 - MAY 2023

Development of new features, and directly fixing bugs sent by the customer on TRUST Plataform.

Furthermore, I was responsible for creating, together with a team, the project's international expansion, to serve international clients, from the US and Mexico.

the tools used for this are, Reactjs, javascript, Context Api, Hooks, scss

### Tech lead / Frontend developer, Networkme, Porto

JANUARY 2021 - MARCH 2022

development first mvp, and all versions of networkme app, from scratch. This platform impact 10k users from mentors to students, giving students the opportunity to connect and chat with mentors, take career simulators, apply for internships, all inside the platform.

This platform are made with reactjs, javascript, material ui, axios, styled components and microsoft communication services.

### Frontend Developer, Bet Protocol, Braga

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2021

Development new frontend features and games with reactjs, javascript, animations, styled component, to BetProtocol application.

BetProtocol is a platform to enable entrepreneurs and developers create betting app in minutes without coding. React and Node.js.

#### **Details**

Pelotas Brasil +55 53 984333852 alissoblaas@gmail.com

#### Links

<u>Linkedin</u> github

#### **Skills**

Communication Skills
Leadership
Analytical Thinking Skills
Project Management
Engineering
Frontend Development

Mobile Development

## Frontend Developer, DevBorne

SEPTEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2020

In this project, we use react native to create a property rental application, with contracts within the app, this impacting when renting a property, without having to have contact with real estate

Stacks used: Redux, react native, git

## Frontend Developer, Fixxer, Pelotas

JANUARY 2018 - AUGUST 2019

My first professional experience gave me the opportunity to learn quickly and understand how a business works.

As the focus was apps and PWA, I worked with: React, React native (w/ redux), and IONIC, besides webpages with html, css, js.

# **Education**

**Computer Science, UFPEL** 

2015

# **Courses**

Javascript course, HCODE

2019